18 chapter 19 of Black Beauty this LibriVox recording is in the public
domain Black Beauty by Anna Su chapter 19 Only Ignorance I do not know how long I was
ill. Mr. Bond, the horse doctor came every day. One day he bled me; John held a pale
for the blood. I felt very faint after it and thought I should die, and I believe
they all thought so too. Ginger and Mery legs had been moved
into the other stable, so that I might be quiet, for the fever made me very quick
of hearing; any little no noise seemed quite loud, and I could tell everyone's
footstep going to and from the house. I knew all that was going
on. One night John had to give me a draft
Thomas Green came in to help him. After I had taken it and John had made me as
comfortable as he could, he said he should stay half an hour to see how the medicine
settled. Thomas said he would stay with him, so they went and sat down on a bench
that had been brought into Mery leg's stall, and put down the L Lon at their
feet, that I might not be disturbed with the light. For a while both men sat silent,
and then Tom Green said in a low voice: “I
wish, John, you'd say a bit of a kind word to Joe. The boy is quite brokenhearted he
can't eat his meals, and he can't smile.
He says he knows it was all his fault, though he is sure he did the best he
knew, and he says if Beauty dies no one will ever speak to him again. It goes to
my heart to hear him. I think you might give him just a word he's not a bad
boy.” After a short pause JN said slowly, “You must not be too hard upon me,
Tom. I know he meant no harm, I never said
he did; I know he is not a bad boy. But
you see, I am sore myself; that horse is the pride of my heart, to say nothing of
his being such a favorite with the master and mistress; and to think that
his life may be flung away in this manner is more than than I can bear. But
if you think I'm hard on the boy I will try to give him a good word tomorrow
that is, I mean if Beauty is better.” “Well, John, thank you. I knew you
did not wish to be too hard, and I'm glad you see it was only
ignorance.” John's voice almost startled me as he answered: “Only ignorance! only ignorance!
how can you talk about only ignorance?
Don't you know that it is the worst thing in the world, next to wickedness?—
?—and which does the most mischief heaven only knows. If people can say, 'Oh! I did
not know, I did not mean any harm,' they think it is all right. I suppose Martha
mwash did not mean to kill that baby when she dosed it with Dal and soothing
syrups; but she did kill it, and was tried for manslaughter.” “And serve her right, too,”
said Tom. “A woman should not undertake to nurse a tender little child without
knowing what is good and what is bad for it.” “Bill starky continued Jon did not mean
to frighten his brother into fits when he dressed up like a ghost and ran after
him in the moonlight; but he did; and that bright, handsome little fellow, that might
have been the pride of any mother's heart is just no better than an idiot,
and never will be, if he lives to be 80 years
old. You were a good deal cut up yourself, Tom, two weeks ago, when those young
ladies left your hot house door open, with a frosty east wind blowing right in;
you said it killed a good many of your plants.” “A good many!” said Tom; “there was
not one of the tender cuttings that was not nipped off. I shall have to strike
all over again, and the worst of it is that I don't know where to go to get
fresh ones. I was nearly mad when I came in and saw what was
done.” “And yet,” said John I'm sure the young ladies did not mean it; it was only
ignorance.” I heard no more of this conversation, for the medicine did well
and sent me to sleep, and in the morning I felt much better; but I often thought
of John's words when I came to know more of the
world end of chapter